Register to The Richard Donovan Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Donovan's Works, 1913-1963; Series VII; 10 Boxes
  - Donovan's Works - Oversize, VII.C
    - Suite for piano, no. 2., 6 items. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      American Composers Alliance publication, 1955
      Black-line print (3).
      Plan for first movement (black-line print).
      First movement as separate piece entitled Invention.
    - Symphony for chamber orchestra., 3 items. (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Holograph incomplete set of parts, 1936.
      Publisher's proof incomplete copy of score.
    - Symphony in D. Orchestra., 2 items. (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Transparencies (76 p.)
    - [Symphony, unidentified], 1 item. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Terzetto. 2 violins and viola., 4 items. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Holograph score and parts, 1950.
      Valley Music Press publication, 1950.
    - To all you ladies now at land. T or S solo, men's chorus (TTBB) and orchestra., 4 items. (Box 26, Folder 6-7)
      Holograph score (2), 1932.
      Holograph set of parts.
      Suggestions for reduction in orchestration (2 p.)
    - To all you ladies now at land; arr. T or S solo, men's chorus (TTBB) and piano., 3 items. (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Galaxy publications (2 versions), 1932
      Holograph score, 1932.
    - Wilt Thou forget me, Lord? High voice and organ., 1 item. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Woodnotes. Flute, string orchestra, and harp. (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
      Holograph score, 1924, and parts for flute and harp.
      Transparencies, 1939- revised set of parts.
      Black-line print set of parts, and set of revised parts.
      Notes about location of scores and parts, in composer's manuscript (2 p.)
    - Unidentified scraps and sketches (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Works of Other Composers, 1925-1965; Series VIII; 1 Box
  Herein can be found the manuscript and photocopy works of such composers as Violet Archer, Everett Helm, Paul Hindemith, Frank Lewin, Quincy Porter, Halsey Stevens and Yehudi Wyner. These are arranged alphabetically by last name of composer. Mimeograph works are mostly student projects.
  - First snow, no date; Archer, Violet, 1913-2000; 2 photocopies. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Come live with me, no date; Bristol, Frederick; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Tarantella, no date; Creston, Paul, 1906-1985; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Night music I, 1963; Crumb, George, 1929-; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Niruana, no date; Daniel, Cyrus; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - The sorrowing., 1950; Di Bonaventura, Sam; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Ghosts, 1950; Durkee, Charlotte; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Piano duet, 1942; D---, J.; mimeograph. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Voice of the wind, no date; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Creator unknown, possibly Gerschefski (firstname unknown).
  - The owl, no date; Goodale, R.L.; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Works of Other Composers, 1925-1965; Helm, Everett B.; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Alleluia, 1946
      (2 copies)
    - Child's garden of verses, A, no date
    - Eleventh avenue racket, no date
    - Epigrams of John Donne, Four, 1946
    - It is so long, no date
    - Lament, 1941
    - Ode to a pig having his nose bored, no date
    - Prairie waters by night, no date
    - Romance, 1946
    - Shall I compare thee, no date
    - She is not fair, no date
      (3 copies)
  - Dies Irae variations, 1942; Hemingway, Louis; mimeograph. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - The jackrabbit, no date; Herman, Ruth; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Herodiade, 1944; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; offset masters. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - The merry way, 1941; Hively, Wells; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Solo-Cantata, 1947; Kaufmann, Henry W. (Henry William), 1913-1982; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Divertimento, 1942; Lam, George L. (George Lorant), 1909-1970; mimeograph. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Innocence and Experience, 1960; Lewin, Frank; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    Autographed.
  - Music for the White House, 1965; Lewin, Frank; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    (in 3 v.)
  - Night pieces, Three, no date; Lewis, H. Merrills; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - The veil, no date; Lora, Antonio; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Dried petals & thin wine, no date; Maworsky, Morris; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Chansons innocentes, 1957; Maztizano, Salvatore; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Ninna nanna, 1957; Maztizano, Salvatore; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Loveliest of trees, no date; McKinney, Mathilde; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Short suite, Novak, Lionel; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Songs from "Chamber music", no date; Osborne, Willson; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Fight the good fight, no date; Parker, Horatio; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Songs of love, Seven, 1961; Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Variations on a French folk song, 1942; Rudas, Hans-Joachim; mimeograph. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Chorale prelude, 1925; Sessions, Roger, 1896-1985; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Song after Campion, no date; Sly, Allan; holograph. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Forty-eight hours, 1945; Stevens, Halsey; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - [6 songs], 1949; Stevens, Halsey; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Quartet for flute, violin, viola, and cello, no date; Vinitsky, Ruth; mimeograph. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Fantasia for clarinet and bassoon, no date; Weiss, Adolph, 1891-1971; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Ricercare for flute, clarinet, and bassoon, 1936; Weiss, Adolph, 1891-1971; photocopy. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Works of Other Composers, 1925-1965; Wyner, Yehudi, 1929- (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Ah God, 1955; photocopy.
    - Brownie, 1951; holograph.
    - Exeunt, 1954; photocopy.
    - Farewell-Chorale prelude, 1950; photocopy.
    - Fragment for organ, 1957; holograph.
    - Monkeys, 1951; 2 photocopies.
    - Manuscript of Beauvais, 1955; photocopy.
    - Manuscript of St. Rémy at Rheims, 1955; photocopy.
    - O Thou in whose presence - Chorale prelude, 1950; photocopy.
    - Psalm 66, 1950; photocopy autographed.
    - Psalm 119, 1950; photocopy.
    - Sonata per pianoforte, 1954; photocopy.
    - Sun, The, 1951; holograph.
    - When you are old, 1951; photocopy.
- List of Donovan's Works
  - Orchestral
    - Design for radio, for a radio orchestra., 1945
    - Epos., 1963
    - New England Chronicle, an overture., 1947
    - Overture in the form of a scherzo., no date
    - Passacaglia on Vermont folk tunes., 1949
    - Smoke and steel, a symphonic poem., 1932
    - Symphony in D., 1956
    - [Unidentified symphony-sketches], no date
  - For chamber groups
    - Arietta for viola and piano., 1942
    - Fantasia for solo bassoon and 7 instruments., Rev. 1961
    - Music for six., 1961
      Oboe, clarinet, trumpet, violin, cello, piano.
    - Piano trio no. 1 in one movement., 1937
    - Piano trio no. 2, 1963
    - Quartet for oboe and strings., no date
    - Quartet for woodwinds, 1953
      Flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon.
    - Ricercare for oboe and string orchestra., 1938
    - Serenade, 196?
      Oboe, violin, viola, violoncello.
    - Sextet for wind instruments and piano., 1932
    - Soundings, 1953
      Trumpet, bassoon and percussion.
    - Suite for oboe and string orchestra., 1944-1945
    - Symphony for chamber orchestra., 1936
    - Terzetto for 2 violins and viola., 1950
    - Wood-Notes for flute harp, and string orchestra., 1924-1925
  - Keyboard works
    - Adventure for piano., 1956
    - Suite no. 1 for piano, 1932
      Prelude, Hornpipe, Air, Jig.
    - Suite no. 2 for piano, 1953
      Invention, Intermezzo, Elegy, Toccata.
    - Antiphon and chorale for organ., 1955
    - Choral preludes on American folk hymns for organ, Two., 1947
    - Paignion for organ., 1947
  - Choral works for mixed voices SATB or SSATB
    - Forever, O Lord., 1961-1962
    - How great, O Lord, is thy goodness., 1923
    - Madrigals, Three, 1954
      Lull, Vigil, Song from the 2nd floor.
      Published and revised in 1964 as Three Part songs.
    - Old French and Czech Christmas Carols., pref. 1931
    - Savior when night involves the skies., 1920
    - Sing to the Lord., 1926
    - Te Deum., 1921
  - Choral works for Unison singing
    - Mass with organ., 1955
      With optional 2 or 3 part divisions.
    - O Christ of Bethlehem, with piano., 1956
    - Taft Alma Mater, with piano., 1923-1924
  - Choral works for women's voices SSA or SSAA
    - Aye Waukin O! (arr.) with piano., 1926
    - Chanson of the bells of Osenèy, with piano., 1930
    - Choruses for women's voices, Three., 1938
      Unaccompanied.
    - How far is it to Bethlehem? with organ., 1927
    - How should I love? with piano., 1947
    - Hymn to the night., 1947
    - Jacques come here. (arr.), 1931
      With piano.
    - Jesu joy of man's desiring. (arr.), 1927
      With organ.
    - Part song., 1920-1923
    - Part songs, Six. (arr.), 1926
      Oranges and lemons, Dame get up, Frog and crow, Ploughboy in luck, There was a lady, King Arthur.
    - Poems by Eleanor Farjeon, 1938
      For snow, For a mocking voice, The wind blows north.
    - Remember not, O Lord, our offences, 1927
    - Songs of nature, Four, 1953
      Dawn, Wind sings, The yellow lily, Wind of heaven.
  - Choral works for men's voices TTB or TTBB
    - Beau galant, Le (arr.), 1930
    - Fantasy on American folk ballads, 194o
      With piano 4 hands or orchestra.
    - Good ale, 1947
    - Highmount, with orchestra, no date
      Incomplete.
    - I will sing unto the Lord, 1954
    - Magnificat, 1961
    - My name shall be there, 1963
    - Old Bangum, 1946
    - Subdue us through kindness (arr.), 1928
    - To all you ladies now at land, 1932
      With orchestra or piano.
  - Works for solo voice
    - Bingo, with piano, no date
      Incomplete holograph.
    - Fable, A., 1948
      For soprano and piano.
    - Homeward, no date
      Hlograph, several versions.
    - Irish Lullaby, no date
      Holograph.
    - Knight of Sherwood, The, 1930
    - Lewis and Clark, no date
    - Page's road song, A, no date
    - Songs on English texts, 1950
      For medium voice and piano.
    - [Songs], no date
      For whom the bell tolls; vocalise for soprano, violin, viola; Light the lamps up, lamplighter.
    - [Songs], no date
      The pretty lady; the very rich man, The fisherwoman, The crusader, The actress.
    - Untitled song "Blow flakes...", 1913
    - Untitled song for Klare Heavens, 1962
    - Wilt Thou forget me Lord?, no date
      For high voice and organ.
    - A birthday round for G.E.H.; and another round for G.E. Hutchinson, 1958 Jan 30, no date
      Holographs.
      See: I.B. correspondence from Donovan.
  - Other
    - Great Panjandrum himself, The, no date
      Monologue with piano.
    - Trumpet call for commencement, no date
      Sketches only.